Mss.B.H262, H 262.p
American Philosophical Society
E. Newton (Edmund Newton) Harvey papers, 1923-1959
Mss.B.H262, H 262.p
American Philosophical Society
7.0 Linear feet Ca. 7000 items; 19 notebooks
The collection consists of correspondence, notes, memoranda, extracts from publications, reprints, drafts of essays, poems, magazine and newspaper articles, comic strips, popular songs, and other material on bioluminescence, collected principally between 1945-1959 for his History of Luminescence from the Earliest Times until 1900 (American Philosophical Society Memoirs 44, 1957). Other topics are chemistry, military medicine, natural history, and professional associations.
Ca. 7000 items and 19 notebooks (7 linear ft.). C. 5, 600 leaves + 19 vols. of Reports from the Office of Scientific Research & Development, 14 Boxes in total.
Harvey, E. Newton(Edmund Newton),1887-1959.
Box 1-14
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Talbot Howe Waterman and accessioned, 10/--/1961 (1961 1591ms). Gift from Princeton University and accessioned, 1964 (1964 2944ms).
Scope and Contents note
The period covered by this collection constitutes almost the entire period of Harvey's career at Princeton University where he began in 1911 as an instructor of Physiology under E. G. Conklin and went on to become Henry Fairfield Osborne Professor of Biology in 1933 to Processor Emeritus 1956 -59. Before beginning his career at Princeton, Harvey obtained his undergraduate degree in General Science at the University of Pennsylvania in 1909, where he studied under Conklin, H.S. Jennings and John MacFarlane. His graduate studies were pursued at Columbia University under the zoologist Thomas Hunt Morgan, his thesis was entitled "The Permeability of Cells," and he was awareded a Ph.D. in 1911.
In addition to his teaching and research at Princeton, Harvey held a long association with the Wood's Hole Marine Biological Station, making it a practice to conduct and direct research there at some time during every summer. He became a Trustee of the Station in 1929 and later Vice-President in 1942. Nearly all the material in the collection concerning Wood's Hole is contained in Box 9 - #12 files, which has materials relating to Executive Committee Meetings, 1946-47, Budgets, 1945-48, Report of the Additional Funds Committee 1942 (set up to try and procure funds for the Station so that it be transformed into a year round research center and not be restricted to summer research only), there are other letters in file 5 of this box, concerning correspondence between the Trustees and the Rockefeller Foundation about this matter, and Reports of the Felowship Committee 1946.
Besides these details of the Marine Biological Station there is little in the collection pertaining to Harvey's voluminous commitments and dutiies outside his Princeton position. For example, he wa a member of many professional associations among them being the National Academy of Sciences (elected 1934), the American Philosophical Society (1929), the American Association for the Advancement of Science (elected 1910, Fellow, 1921), member of the American Physiological Society (1914) and the Society for Experimental Biology and Medicine (1919) to name but a few. He became managing Editor of the Journal of Cellular and Comparative Physiology, 1932-39, Editor of the Journal of Experimental Biology, 1930-34, Editor of the Biological Buletin 1930-53, and Section Editor of Biological Abstracts 1930-53 of which there is some mention in Box e (Biological Abstracts, 1948-49), where Harvey wanted papers pertaining to bioluminescence to be in his section of general physiology.
Much of this collection concerns Harvey's work in Bioluminescence at Princeton, especially correspondence with scientistis and naturalists throughout the world to make arrangements for the collection of luminous plants and animals and their classification. See - (Barber, H.S., Box 2 - U.S.D.A. Bureau of Entomology, 7 letters 1915-26), (Bowden, Bernald J. Box 2, 10 letters, 1949-50), Chapin, Edward A., Box 2, 1951 of the Smithsonian Institution), (Hastings J. Woodland, Box 3, 1952-56, c. 20 letters), and (Parker, Harry L., Box 4, 1943-46).
It must be said that the bulk of the colelction pertains to the period 1942-46 and Harvey's work at Princeton under the auspices of the various Committees and Subcommittees of teh National Research Council, set up in War-time acting for the Committee of Medical Research of the Office of Scientific Research & Development. Harvey worked as a member of the Subcommittee of Wound Ballistics, 1944-46, Decompression Sickness, 1943-46 and the Subcommittee on Missile Casualties, 1943-46. See Box 5: -Bulletin on Missile Casualties - circulated in installments for members of the Subcommittee with lists of members attending each meeting, #5 files. Bulletins Chariman of the Division of Medical Sciences of teh NRC, discharging these Subcommittees in 1946 after the War had ended. Committee on Aviation Medicine Reports 1940-45 and Committee on Medical Research Reports Nos. 1-79 #5 files, 1944-46. Also Box 6, Committees on Military Medicine of the Division of Medical Sciences of the NRC, with a list of all the names and addresses of these Committees and Subcommittees with an index of names of committee members, 1944. Box 7, Decompression Sickness Mimiographed Reports Nos. 1-20 & 127-469, 1942-45, monthly progress reports, and Final Decompression Sickness Report, #7 files of which Harvey was responsible for the section 'Bubble Formation in Animals." Missile Casualties Reports #11 files 1944-46, and Box 14 which consists totally of Wound Ballistics Reports #24 files 1945 & 1946. For anyone wishing to carry out research into the activities of scientists during the War period this collection would be an excellent source of information. Harvey was also funded at other times by teh Defense Authorities, (See Box 8, Progress Reports, #4 files, 1949-50, Reports to the Office of teh Quartermaster of the Dept. of the Army, on the investigation of using luminous materials for the invention of a nightwriting device).
Throughout the collection, there is much reference to Havey's published works, with many drafts of articles see (Box 7, Evolution of Bioluminescence and its Relation to Cell Respiration), (Box 8 Luminescence of Animals), and (Box 8 A General Survey of Bioluminescence, 1946). Tehre are many rough notes and translations from early works mostly done by a Mrs. Hajo Holborn (Box 5, Casato P. de Inge) and (Box 12 Quotations from Authors re: Fire Files, #3 files), and (Box 2, Academic Press concerning Havey's book "Bioluminescence," published 1952)
Reference to some of Harvey's graduate students are dispersed throughout the files, some in reference to grant proposals of which some are included in the collection. (See Peter S. Marfey, Box 3, 1955-58, c. 30 letters), (Box 3, Howard Mason, 1950-53) (Box 7, "Fish Bioluminescence," grant proposal to NSF 1958-59 including the names of F.H. Johnson and Yata Haneda as research associates). (Box 12, Reports - #6 files, Annual Report to NSF 1957 for project "Biochemistry of Light Production in the Ostracod Crustacean, Cypridina; plus the Grant Proposal 1952), (also Box 12, Report for Research Corporation which funded the project 'Chemical Nature of Cypridina Luceferin, 1952) and (Box 12 Reports of work carried out under grant from the Office of Naval Research, 1952-54 "Chemistry of Light Production in Living Organisms.").
In this collection there are no correspondents whom one could label major, since much of the correspondence between Harvey and others consists of only a few letters, and are mostly concerning the collection of specimens, the remainder of the collection consists of Government reports.
The collection is arranged alphabetically in files and each file being arranged chronologically the way it arrived from Princeton. The unpublished guide follows this pattern and is an alphabetical list of contents.
Biographical/Historical note
Edmund Newton Harvey (Nov. 25, 1887-July 21, 1959) was a physiologist. His interests included bioluminescence, decompression sickness, and tissue damage caused by high velocity missiles.
United States. Office of Scientific Research and Development; Waterman, Talbot H., (Talbot Howe), 1914-; Articles.; Bioluminescence.; Cell physiology.; Chemistry; Comic strips.; Crustacea -- Physiology.; Decompression Sickness; Galley proofs.; Luminescence -- History.; Medicine -- United States.; Military art and science.; Natural history.; Physiology.; Poems.; War wounds.; Wounds and injuries.
- Correspondence
  - Academic Press, Inc.
    Scope and Contents note
    Jacoby, Kurt
  - Anderson, Robert S
  - Andrews, W S
    General note
    See also: Siloxene, in:
  - Archives of Biochemistry.
  - Armstrong, Philip Brownell, 1898-
  - Arnott, T Davidson
  - Arvy, Lucie
  - Aydlette, Dorothy
    Eastman Kodak Company; Garvin, Elsie L.
  - Ashmore, J
  - Ballentine, Robert
  - Barber, H S
    Phillips, E.F.; See also: Parker, Harry L., in: See also: Dahlgren, Ulric; and Diplocladon, in:
  - Bargmann, Mrs. V
  - Baylor, Mrs. Martha
  - Beams, H W
  - Beebe, William
  - Bellamy, W Dexter
  - Belloc, G
  - Birkhoff, Garrett -Material removed from Pamphlets # 2, 1944-1945; Birkhoff, Garrett, 1911-1966
    Correspondence between Harvey and Garrett Birkhoff, concerning torpedo found together; Harvard University, Division of War Research, Applied Mathematics Group
  - Bersis, Dem S
  - Biological Abstracts
    Flynn, John E.; Butler, E. G.
  - Bioluminescence Ad Hoc Advisory Group.
  - Blinks, Lawrence
  - Bonhomme, Ch
  - Bossard, W D K
  - Bowden, Bernard J
    Taylor, W. J.
  - Braun, Armin C.
  - Briquet, Raul C, Jr.
    See also: Dobzhansky, Theodosius G., in:
  - Bronk, Detlev Wulf, 1897-
    McElroy, William D.
  - Brown, Charles Arthur
  - Buchner, Paul
  - Buck, John B # 1
    Williams, Carroll [Milton](1916-) See: Dahlgren, Ulric; and Fire-fly materials, in: See: Mason, Howard S
  - Buck, John B # 2
    See also: Luminescences (various), in:
  - Buck, John B # 3
    See also: Students on fire-files, in:
  - Bullock, T H
  - Burnett and Son.
  - Buschke, A
  - Calvert, Philip P
  - Calvin, Jack
  - Cambridge University Press
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington.
  - Carson, Rachel L
    See also: Luminescences (various), in: See also: Guggenheim, John Simon, Memorial Foundation, in:
  - Cartland, G F
  - Case, James
  - Chambers, William
  - Chang, Joseph J
  - Chang, S O
  - Chapin, Edward A
  - Chase, Henry B., Jr.
  - Ciusa, Walter
  - Cleaves, Howard H
  - Coblentz, W W
    Duggar, B M
  - Coolidge, Harold J
  - Cormier, Milton J
    Gates, Marshall
  - Correspondence (Misc.) -Material removed from Pamphlets # 1, 1921-1957
    Night-writing device; Committee on Growth, National Research Council: Application for a Grant in Cancer Research (14 Nov. 1946); Includes a paper by Harvey, entitled "Merkel Henry Jacobs and the Study of Cell Permeability"; Correspondence, re: bioluminescence research; correspondents: R. H Kent of the Laboratory of Physiology, Yale University School of Medicine (July 17, 1944); Hurst H. Shoemaker of the Gulf Coast Research Laboratory, Ocean Springs, MI. (June 27, 1957)
  - Costa Lima, A
  - Crisp, D J
  - Crocco, L
  - Crowell, Sears
  - Crowley, Ralph M
  - Cruickshank, John
  - Cushing, D H
  - Dahlquist, Ed
  - Daniels, Farrington
  - Darlington, P J, Jr.
    See: Dahlgren, Ulric, and other notes.
  - Davis, Watson
    See also: Science Service, Inc., in:
  - DeMent, Jack
  - Dennell, Ralph
  - Deichmann, Elizabeth
  - Dieke, Gerhard H
  - Driese, Don N
  - DuBois, Raphael
  - Dubos, Rene Jules, 1901
  - Edmunds, Leland N, Jr.
  - Elliott, Hugh K
  - Evans, Charles A
    See also: Vx Tumor, in:
  - Faure-Fremiet, E
  - Fleischeuer, R
  - Forbes, William T M
    Comstock, William P.; Brower, A E; Freeman, T N; Richards, A Glenn.
  - Fox, William
    Freeman, T N
  - Fruton, Joseph S
    See also: Childs Memorial Fund, 1945, in:
  - Fulton, John F
  - General Electric Company.
    Hughes, Dale C
  - Gensler, Walter J
  - Giese, Arthur C
    See: Fish bioluminescence materials.
  - Glass, Bentley, 1906-; Glass, Bentley, 1906-2005
  - Goldforb, Abraham J
    See also: Roof, Betty Sams, in:
  - Grant materials
  - Gudger, Eugene Willis, 1866-1956
    See also: Luminous phenomena. schistostega, cats..., in:
  - Guggenheim, John Simon, Memorial Foundation
    Moe, Henry Allen; Johnson, Frank H.
  - Gunther, Klaus
  - Gutman, Walter K
  - Hallister, Gloria
  - Hancock, J E H
  - Hanada, Yata
    See also: Bioluminescence, Diplocladon, Fish bioluminescence materials, Luminescences (various), Parpart, A.K., in: Tuthill, Leonard D.
  - Harris, Gerbert I
  - Harrison, George R
  - Harvey, Harriet
  - Hastings, J Woodland
    See also: Bacteria and fungi, and Bio-luminescence, in: See also: Luminescent fungi, in: See also: Squids, in:
  - Hatt, Robert T.
  - Healy, Frank J
  - Henry, Arthur M
  - Henshaw, Paul S
    b
  - Hess, Carolyn
  - Heyde, H
  - Hilder, Brett
  - Hollaender, Alexander, 1898-
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine - Friedmann, Ulrich, in:
  - Hulen, Hobart
  - Hundley, James M
    See: Translations: electrolum and ignis lambens: aurora borealis
  - Hunt, F L
  - Hunt, Mrs. J H
    Ryan, Francis J.
  - Huntsman, A G
  - Inoué, Shinya, 1921
    Correspondence.
  - Ishikawa, Chiyomatsu
  - Jackson, Eugene B
  - Jegier, Sygmund
  - Johnson, Frank H
    Nicol, J A C; Coolidge, H J; Eisenhart, Luther Phaler; American Philosophical Society.
    See also: Haneda, Y. "Luminous organisms.;" and Luminescent fungi, in: See also: Guggenheim Memorial Foundation; Parpart, A.K., in: See also: Wellman, Frederick L.; in:
  - Johnson, Walter J
    See also: Booksellers, in:
  - Jullien, A
  - Kageyama, Tosaku
  - Kanda, Sakyo
    See: Bioluminescence
  - Kasha, Michael
  - Kautsky, L
  - Kellogg, Remington
  - Kirkpatrick, T W
  - Kluyver, A J
  - Knobloch, J W
  - Koch, Anton
  - Koernicke, M
  - Koller, Lewis R
    Wiley, John, & Sons
  - Koser, Bruce L
  - Kraus, Frederick W
  - Lamb, Arthur B
  - Landsteiner, Karl, 1868-1943
    See also: Chicken tumor, in:
  - Lane, Frank W
  - Leavitt, Richard A
  - Levinson, Stuart A
  - Lewis, H.K., & Company, Ltd.
  - Life (Magazine)
  - Linschitz, Henry
  - Litsey, John B
  - Locke, Murray S
  - Loomis, H F
  - Lower, George G
    See: Luminous phenomena. Schistostega..., in:
  - Lutz, Frank E
    See also: Light in phosphorus and fluorescence, in:
  - McDermott, Frank A[lexander]
    See also: Dahlgren, Ulric, in: See also: Luminescent fungi, in: See also: "Nature and the Doctor", in:
  - The Macmillan Company
  - Macrae, Ruth
    See: Luminescent fungi, in:
  - McElroy, William Dale, 1906-
    See: Bronk, Detlev W., in:
  - Marfey, Peter Swiatopolk
    Quill, Laurence L; LeRoy, D J; Smith, Homer P; Craig, Lyman S; Klotz, Irving M; Chase, Aurin; Brown, A J; Woodrow, Raymond J; Chang, J; Burk, Dean.
  - Marine Biological Laboratory [Woods Hole, Mass.]
    Montgomery, Mrs. T.H., Jr.
  - Mason, Howard S
    Buck, John.
  - Masuda, Yoshiro
  - Mayr, Ernst, 1904-
  - Merriman, Daniel
  - Miller, Charles G
  - Miller, Harry M, Jr.
    See also: Parker, Harry L., in:
    Laroza, Enrique
  - Millikan, Glenn
    See: Cypridine Luminiscene, in:
  - Moore, A R
  - Moore, J Percy
    See also: Pickford, Grace, in:
  - Morrison, F F
  - Murphy, Robert Cushman, 1887-1973
  - Muschel, Louis H
  - National Research Council Publications Office
    Hillegeist, M R
  - Navajas, Eduardo
  - Naval Research Library
  - Nichols, Edward L
  - Nicoll, Robert W
  - Niederhauser, W S
  - Nijhoff, Martinus
  - Nims, Leslie F
  - Nishizaki, Ichro
    See: Luminescences (various), in:
  - Nygaard, Kaare K
  - Ormsbee, Richard A
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine - McKee, R. W., in:
  - Owen, David M
    Edgerton, H E; Hoadley, Lloyd D.
  - Owens, R B
    Dahlgren, Ulric.
  - Packard, Charles
  - Parker, George Howard, 1864-1955
    Sumner, F B.
  - Parker, Harry L
    Barber, H S; Miller H M, Jr.; Annard, P N; Hoyt, Avery S.
  - Parpart, Arthur K
    Johnson, Frank H.; Woodrow, Ray; Haneda, Yata.
  - Patka, Robert E
  - Patterson Screen Company
    Patterson, Carl V S.
  - Pergamon Press, Inc.
  - Pickford, Grace E
    See: Bioluminescence; and Fish physiology paper, in:
    Moore, J Percy; Taning, A Vedel.
  - Pinci, A R
  - Pleas, C E
    Walker, Robert Sparks.
  - Presses Universitaires de France
  - Princeton University Press
  - Rainwater, Clarence S
  - Raley, Charles F., Jr.
  - Raman, Sir C V
  - Ramsay, Graeme W
  - The Reader's Digest
    Veit, Mrs. Rosamund Reed; Mohony, Walter, B., Jr.
  - Rehn, James A G
  - Reid, Evans B
  - Richards, William T
  - Rickard, G L
    Dahlgren, Ulric; Ditmars, Raymond L.
  - Rickes, Larry
  - Riggs, Austen F
  - Ritola, Lilian
  - Robbins, William Jacob, 1890-
    See also: National Academy of Sciences, 1942-1943; and NAS, 1943-1944, in:
  - Roberts, T W
  - Rothstein, Jerome
  - Salle, A J
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine, in:
  - Saunders, W B, Company
    See also: American Anthropologist, in:
    Mink, S. [J.]
  - Sawaya, Paulo
    See also: Bryozoa and enteropneusta, in:
  - Schmitt, Francis O[tto], 1903-
    See also: Journal of Experimental Medicine - Gross, Francis O., in:
  - Schneider, Herbert W
  - Schoepple, Gordon
  - Schullian, Dorothy M
    See also: Rivinus and Boehme, De Noctu Lucentibus, in:
  - Schultz, Leonard P
  - Schultz, Stuart
  - Scribner's, Charles, Sons.
    Woodbridge, Jane.
  - Sears, Mary
  - Shirai, T
  - Shoup, C S
  - Sie, Edward
  - Sigma Xi lecture
  - Simmons, David J
    Schanberg, Saul M.
  - Smith, Leland L
    Bailey, Philip S; Henze, Henry R; Watt, George W.
  - Smith, Osgood R
  - Sotheran, Henry, Ltd.
  - Sosa, Julio Maria
  - Stanton, Madeline
    See also: Report on bubble formation. no. 77, in:
  - Stechert-Shafner, Inc.
  - Steele, Richard H
  - Strehler, Bernard L
    See: Notes on luminescence - miscellany; and Rays from organisms, in:
    Slauer, R G.
  - Swan, Emery F
    See also: Cultivation of noctiluca, in:
  - Swope, Gerard, Jr.
    See also: Marine biological laboratory, in:
  - Sylvania Electric Products, Inc.
    Slauer, R. C.
  - Taylor, Preston
  - Thone, Frank
  - Todres, Irving
  - Tracerlab, Inc.
  - Tregouboff, G
  - Tsuji, Frederick I
  - Tung, S K
  - Turner, Ruth D
    See also: Mollusks, in:
  - Ullrich, Gilbert R
  - Urban and Schwarzenberg
  - Vadala, Eleanor
  - Van der Kirk, G J M
  - Veeriah, Kota
  - Walker, Robert Sparks
    See also: Pleas, C. E., in:
  - Webster, W L
  - Welch, Arnold D
  - Wellman, Frederick L
    Johnson, Frank H.
  - Westwood, Richard W
  - Wheeler, Louis C
  - Whipple, Gerald H
  - Whitley, A H
  - Wick, Frances G
  - Williams, Harold H
  - Wood, R W
    See also: Dahlgren, Ulric, and other notes, in:
    Bernier, R.
  - Yale University Press
- Papers
  Eastman Kodak Company; Garvin, Elsie L.; Hillegeist, M R
  - Adenosin triphosphate and bioluminiscence of various organisms.
  - Animals and the Sea # 1
    Amaniya, I
  - Animals and the Sea # 2
  - Bacteria and Fungi # 1
    Hastings, J W; Kanzmann, W.
  - Bacteria and Fungi # 2
  - Barnes, Dale # 1
  - Barnes, Dale # 2
  - Bartholin, Thomas. "De Luce Animalium" # 1
    Hegeler, Inge; Birkelund, Palle; Coleman-Norton, P R.
  - Bartholin, Thomas. "De Luce Animalium" # 2
  - Bartholin, Thomas. "De Luce Animalium" # 3
  - Bartholin, Thomas. "De Luce Animalium" # 4
    Holborn, Mrs. Annemarie; Fulton, John F.
  - Bartholin, Thomas. "De Luce Animalium" # 5
  - Battle Wounds -- Material removed from Pamphlets # 4, 1944
    Battle wounds
  - Biological engineering
    Berrill, N J.
  - Bioluminescence
  - Bioluminescence # 1
    Loomis, H F; Brown, Barnum; Davenport, Demarest; Schmitt, Waldo L; Atz, James W; Hastings, J Woodland; Redfield, Alfred C; Kanda, Sakyo; Pickford, Grace E; Dahlgren, Ulric; Bruner, Lawrence; Costello, Donald P.; Pierantoni, Umberto; Weeks, Edward; Buddenbrock, W von; Haneda, Yata.
  - Bioluminescence # 2
    Pickford, Grace E.; Dahlgren, Ulric; Bruner, Lawrence; Davenport, Demarest; Costello, Donald P.; Pierantoni, Umberto; Weeks, Edward; Buddenbrock, W von; Haneda, Yata.
  - Bioluminescence crustacea.
  - Bioluminescence in the sea.
    Separated Materials note
    Redfield, Alfred C.; Fromm, Winfield E.; Cutter, Charles N.; Grant, Wilson C.; Chadwell, Harris M.; Pitzer K S.
  - Bioluminiscence Notes - Miscellaneous
    Biologcial Abstracts.
  - Book reviews (Inorganic luminiscence) # 1
  - Book reviews (Inorganic luminiscence) # 2
  - Book reviews (Inorganic luminiscence) # 3
  - Boyle, Robert, Quotations # 1
  - Boyle, Robert, Quotations # 2
  - Boyle, Robert, Quotations # 3
  - Boyle, Robert, Quotations # 4
  - Bryozoa and Enteropneusta
    Sawaya, Paulo; Bassler, R S; Blagg, Amy Elizabeth; Rogick, Mary Dora.
  - Bubble Formation # 1
  - Bubble Formation # 2
  - Bulletin on Missle Causalties # 1
  - Bulletin on Missle Causalties # 2
  - Bulletin on Missle Causalties # 3
  - Bulletin on Missle Causalties # 4
  - Bulletin on Missle Causalties # 5
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 1
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 2
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 3
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 4
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 5
    Fulton, John F.
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 6
    Fulton, John F.; Bronk, Detlev.
  - Bulletins on Decompression Sickness # 7
    Weed, Lewis H.
  - Casato, P. De Inge...
    Holborn, Annemarie.
  - Chemiluminiscence and Oxydation Notes
  - Classification of Fish and Luminiscent Species # 1
    Waterman, T[albot] H[owe]; Parr, A E.
  - Classification of Fish and Luminiscent Species # 2
  - Collembola
  - Committee on Aviation Medicine. Reports.
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 1-5
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 6-10
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 11-14
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 15-19
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 20-24
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 25-29
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 30-33
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 34-39
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos.40-44
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 45-49
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 50-54
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 55-59
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 60-65
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 66-71
  - Committee on Medical Research. Reports, Nos. 72-78
  - Committee on Military Medicine
  - Ctenophora.
    Deichmann, Elizabeth.
  - Cultivation of Noctiluca
    Swan, Every F.; Thompson, Thomas G.
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 1
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 2
    Kluyver, A J; Schouwenburg, K L van
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 3
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 4
    Millikan, Glenn.
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 5
  - Cypridine luminiscence # 6
  - Dahlgren, Ulric and Other Notes # 1
    Barber, H. S.; Most, S O; McDermott, F. Alexander; Vosburgh, F. G.; Poggenpohl, Andrew; Lippincott, Charles.
    See also: Owens, R. B., in: See also: Rickard, G. L., in: See also: Shrimp; and Siloxene, in: See also: Luminous phenomena. Schistostega, cats..., in: See also: Luminescent fungi, in:
  - Dahlgren, Ulric and Other Notes # 2
    Darlington, P.J., Jr.; Wood, R. W.; Buch, John B.; Winkelried Bertonoi, Arnold de; Lutz, Frank E.; DeCosta, Lima A.; Schulze, Alberto; Forsythe, W. E.
  - Dahlgren, Ulric. Cypridina Hilgendorfii.
  - Decompression Monograph # 1
    Fulton, John F.; Fox, Francis E.; Livingston, Burton E[dward] (1875-1948).
  - Decompression Monograph # 2
    Fulton, John, F.; Fishbein, Morris; Bailey, Herbert S., Jr.; Code, Charles F.; Turner, Kenneth B.
  - Decompression Sickness. Mimeographed Reports, Nos. 1-20